<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aaron&#39;s Statistics Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aaron&#39;s Statistics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Genocide Reading Blog Post</title>
      <link>/post/genocide-reading-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/genocide-reading-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>http://www.fast.ai/2017/11/02/ethics/
Genocide through Data Science is without a doubt something that is extremely scary. Pre-existing beliefs make their way into models and then are used to convince other people on decisions that effect the lives of hundreds, thousands, even millions or billions of people. Computers are products of their environment, algorithms don&amp;rsquo;t make things up from nowhere. Data is fed into them that influnces their models based on socio-economic norms and standards from the past which was much less open minded and equality oriented than the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISLR Chapter 8</title>
      <link>/post/islr-ch-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/islr-ch-8/</guid>
      <description>ISLR Ch 8 #5, #7, #9
\(5\). Suppose we produce ten bootstrapped samples from a data set containing red and green classes. We then apply a classification tree to each bootstrapped sample and, for a specific value of X, produce 10 estimates of \(P (Class is Red|X)\):
 0.1, 0.15, 0.2, 0.2, 0.55, 0.6, 0.6, 0.65, 0.7, and 0.75.  There are two common ways to combine these results together into a single class prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science in the News</title>
      <link>/post/data-science-in-the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-science-in-the-news/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about the &amp;ldquo;Hamilton Dashboard&amp;rdquo; this is a cool website that shows the influence of Russia on twitter. As of the time I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post they are talking about &amp;lsquo;#trumpville&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;#DACA&amp;rsquo;. I want to talk about this because Of this video. What is going on in the political landscape of our country is as its never been since the foundation of the country.
This is simple data out there and it tells a great story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISLR Chapter 5</title>
      <link>/post/islr_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/islr_ch5/</guid>
      <description>ISLR Ch 5: #3, #5
3 We now review k-fold cross-validation. \((a)\) Explain how k-fold cross-validation is implemented.
k-fold cross-validation is implemented by chosing a number of folds and then splitting the data into k nearly evenly partitioned
\((b)\) What are the advantages and disadvantages of k-fold cross-validation relative to:
 The validation set approach?    Having more than one set of training data allows for a better model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISLR Chapter 4</title>
      <link>/post/islr_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/islr_ch4/</guid>
      <description>ISLR Ch4 Exercises #5, #13   We now examine the differences between LDA and QDA.    \((a)\) If the Bayes decision boundary is linear, do we expect LDA or QDA to perform better on the training set? On the test set?   On the training set of data you would expect LDA to perform better than the QDA if the decision boundary is linear and there are relatively few training observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISLR Ch 3</title>
      <link>/post/islr_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/islr_ch3/</guid>
      <description>ISLR Ch3 Exercises #4, #15   I collect a set of data (n = 100 observations) containing a single predictor and a quantitative response. I then fit a linear regression model to the data, as well as a separate cubic regression, i.e. \(Y = \beta_{0}+\beta_{1}X+\beta_{2}X^{2}+\beta_{3}X^{3}+\epsilon\).    \((a)\) Suppose that the true relationship between X and Y is linear, i.e. \(Y = \beta_0 + \beta_{1}X + \epsilon\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISLR Ch2</title>
      <link>/post/islr_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/islr_ch2/</guid>
      <description>ISLR Ch2 Exercises: #1, #2, #4, #10   For each of parts (a) through (d), indicate whether we would generally expect the performance of a flexible statistical learning method to be better or worse than an inflexible method. Justify your answer.    The sample size n is extremely large, and the number of predictors p is small.    Because of the abundance of data n the flexible method will perform better than the inflexible method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make File in R</title>
      <link>/post/make-for-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/make-for-r/</guid>
      <description>This is the tutorial for my makefile for r, My makefile is as follows:
all: gapminder gapminder: Rscript -e &amp;quot;knitr::knit(&#39;gapminder.Rmd&#39;);/ rmarkdown::render(&#39;gapminder.Rmd&#39;,&#39;html_document&#39;)&amp;quot; clean: rm -rf *.md rm -rf *.html  What this makefile does is call the knit package on my gapminder.Rmd file and then call the rmarkdown::render() function on my file to knit the file and render it to .html
You can find the link to that html here!
In order to format the page to look nice I lie a bit in how my code is represented to the viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

Key features:
 Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Extensible via color themes and widgets/plugins Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Multilingual and easy to customize  Color Themes Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>